<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Keivan Shah</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Keivan Shah</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rock Paper Scissors Battle Simulator</title><link>/posts/rps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rps/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="show-me-what-you-made">Show me what you made!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Yeah, no point going through the technical details if you dont like what I made! So here: &lt;a href="https://keivan-shah.github.io/RPS/">https://keivan-shah.github.io/RPS/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://keivan-shah.github.io/RPS/">
 &lt;img src="/img/rps.png" alt="RPS Simulator" class="center" style="border-radius: 8px;" />

&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is a Rock-Paper-Scissor battle simulator! 33 players of each type are added to a box, they follow a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brownian_motion">Brownian motion&lt;/a> i.e. random movement and then at each encounter, the players change to one that is the most powerful amongst them follwing the classic rules of RPS! They do so till only one type remains which is declared the winner!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Github Contribution Graph Grafiti</title><link>/posts/contri-hack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/contri-hack/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Whenever you open someone&amp;rsquo;s profile on Github, it shows you a neat summary of all the historical contributions that you have done and showcases it as a neat &lt;code>53x7&lt;/code> grid. The grid shows the number of commits and other interactions that the user performed on each day over the last year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I have started working professionally and I use a different Github account for it, the contribution graph on my personal Github account has been quite empty lately. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at my contribution graph before I decided to draw my name all over it :P&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>L-System</title><link>/posts/lsystem/random_lsystem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lsystem/random_lsystem/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today I came across a new term: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L-system">L-System&lt;/a> and I found it quite fascinating. The idea that simple rules can lead to the formation of complex structures that might be used to model tree and organism growth and also generate &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fractal#Introduction">fractals&lt;/a> is intriguing to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/L-System/">
 &lt;img src="/img/lsystem_tree.png" alt="L-System (FF[&amp;#43;&amp;#43;F[-F]&amp;#43;F][F[&amp;#43;F]-F][--F[&amp;#43;F]-F])" class="center" style="border-radius: 8px; width: 300px" />

&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This image was created with help of L-System and it&amp;rsquo;s visualization. It can also be used to model far more complicated tree structures. If you are interested you can checkout how I created this image &lt;strong>&lt;a href="/L-System/">here&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> and the code for the same can be found &lt;a href="https://github.com/keivan-shah/L-System">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating your Static Website</title><link>/posts/creating-a-new-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/creating-a-new-website/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Creating and hosting a website is something that many of us wondered if not tried to do. While hosting a dynamic website is comparatively challenging, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to host a simple &lt;a href="https://techterms.com/definition/staticwebsite">static website&lt;/a> with something like &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages&lt;/a>. So in this post, I try to help people setup up what could potentially be your first website :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> Being a developer I just assume that people know the basics of computer programming and can get by with using a little bit of command-line. While I do assume the above, I know that it is not obvious to everyone so don&amp;rsquo;t get discouraged if you do not get things!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey, &lt;em>Keivan Shah&lt;/em> here. A curious engineer trying to make his living working as a Software Developer! Currently I am working as a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-frequency_trading">HFT&lt;/a> Developer @ &lt;a href="https://silverleafcaps.com/">Silverleaf&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for stopping by my website! Currently I am not sure what I intend to do with this website but hopefully I will figure it out someday :D&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>